{
    "id": "2ccb1b75026e4adc9b2fb0569ff6b3ac",
    "title": "Prepositions Exercise",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "It is too late to go out now. …………………., it’s starting to rain.",
            "description": "Besides and in addition can mean also.",
            "answers": [
                "Beside",
                "Besides",
                "In addition"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "97aa3ee6ff3a4ccca8253a5049601aed"
        },
        {
            "question": "There were ………………… ten people at the meeting.",
            "description": "Under means less than or younger than.",
            "answers": [
                "under",
                "below",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "952f0ad0237549ef9333d517bc9b0be7"
        },
        {
            "question": "She is well ……………………… average in intelligence.",
            "description": "Above is used in cases where we think of a vertical scale.",
            "answers": [
                "above",
                "over",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "9f03e6f5522d4d36895870c3d328c408"
        },
        {
            "question": "We lost the championship …………………………. working very hard.",
            "description": "In spite is a preposition. Although and however are conjunctions.",
            "answers": [
                "in spite of",
                "although",
                "however"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "af48a04700624cf0a9c7453a4cf752e7"
        },
        {
            "question": "We understood him ……………………… his strange accent.",
            "description": "Despite can be used in the same way as in spite of. It is more formal.",
            "answers": [
                "despite",
                "in spite of",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "c2eeb4e0f0e44ea09bbe401a7aa0347a"
        },
        {
            "question": "I could not enjoy the movie ……………………….. the headache.",
            "description": "Because of is the opposite of in spite of.",
            "answers": [
                "in spite of",
                "because of",
                "despite"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "e570c98c427a4617ab45bee993433db0"
        },
        {
            "question": "The cat is ……………………. the roof again.",
            "description": "We use on to talk about the positions of things.",
            "answers": [
                "on",
                "onto",
                "at"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "e8e48cee9d404e76b50193ae51a8086c"
        },
        {
            "question": "How did that cat get ……………………… the roof?",
            "description": "We use onto to talk about directions and destinations.",
            "answers": [
                "on",
                "in",
                "onto",
                "into"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "61099c3e82cd4eb39f949701cc1b3009"
        },
        {
            "question": "Can you translate this letter …………………… German?",
            "description": "We normally use into after verbs suggesting change.",
            "answers": [
                "in",
                "into",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "affe572b6df44552b81c48378b606143"
        },
        {
            "question": "I prefer swimming ……………………. walking.",
            "description": "Prefer is followed by to.",
            "answers": [
                "to",
                "over",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "03afe704b229469da869d607e85aa827"
        },
        {
            "question": "Can you go with Madhu ………………………… me today?",
            "description": "Instead of is the preposition. Instead without of is an adverb.",
            "answers": [
                "instead",
                "instead of",
                "without"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "0ab40a4e895a46f2ba9afc86779ee143"
        },
        {
            "question": "Wine can be made …………………….. blackberries.",
            "description": "We use make from to talk about changing a material into a completely different form to make something.",
            "answers": [
                "of",
                "with",
                "from"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "c302ab1d943544c297c63d4fdaf04968"
        }
    ]
}